主啊
O lord...
我走的可是正途
Am I on the right path?
如果是  请你
If so, please...
给我个启示吧
give me a sign.
烂咖啡最糟糕了
Nothing worse than bad coffee.
玛莎  没什么事吧
Martha? Is everything okay?
你告诉我啊  丫头
You tell me, kiddo.
我们上次在一起时  你和理查德还
Last time we were together, you and Richard were,
缠缠绵绵呢
Uh, "Ha ha," you know?
而只过了几周
And now, just a few short weeks later,
你和理查德就...
you and Richard are, uh "Pfft," you know?
很复杂
It's complicated.
他上两次离婚也都如此
So were his last two divorces.
天呐  玛莎  我们不会离婚的
Oh, god. Martha, we're not getting a divorce.
算我老派
Well, call me old-fashioned,
但已婚夫妇不是都住一起的吗
but don't married couples live together?
是啊  但情况复杂
Yes, but I-it's complicated,
我有些事要处理
and... and I'm working through a few things.
理查德告诉我了
Richard told me that...
然后就宣布说要把你赢回来
Right before he declared he was going to win you back.
你也知道  我儿子有很多特点
Look, as you know, my son is a lot of things...
有优点  有缺点
Some of them good, some of them not so good.
但你总能指望他
But he is someone you can always count on.
这可不常有  丫头
And that is a rare thing, kiddo.
嗯
Uh, yeah.
好的  我让警探马上出警
All right. I'll have detectives respond.
玛莎  对不起  有案子
Uh, Martha, I'm sorry. Uh, there's a murder, and...
凯瑟琳  亲爱的
Katherine, darling...
坦诚对自己
Look, be honest with yourself
也坦诚对你丈夫
and be honest with your husband.
我以为第二胎能少花钱呢
Man, I thought the second kid would be cheaper.
但珍妮什么都想买新的
But Jenny... she wants all new stuff.
你真该看看她选的婴儿车
You should see the baby stroller that she picked out.
真的  我可能得再找份全职工作了
Seriously, I might have to get a second full-time job.
或者你在第一份工作上多挣点
Or you can make more money from your first job.
怎么  加班吗
What, like overtime?
不  升职
No... promotion.
警长考试一周后举行  我们去考吧
Sergeant's exam is in a week. Let's take it.
一周  我们哪来的时间学习啊
A week?! When are we gonna have time to study?
能多难
How hard can it be?
威尔基警长就通过了
Sergeant Wilkie passed,
他简直差一条染色体就是尼安德特人了
and he's, like, a chromosome away from a Neanderthal.
或许你是对的
Maybe you're right.
好吧  我打去总部  给咱俩报名
Okay, I'll call 1pp, sign us both up.
早上好
Good morning.
容我有幸向二位介绍
Allow me the pleasure of introducing you
大卫·约翰逊  52岁  胸部中一枪
to Dave Johnson, 52, single GSW to the sternum.
凶手趁他祈祷时打死了他
Killer popped him while he was praying.
你俩排练过吗
What? Did you guys rehearse that?
都做过祭坛助手
Former altar boys.
嗯  大概是下意识反应什么的
Yeah. Probably an involuntary reflex or something.
从伤口看
Wound suggests he was shot
他是昨晚8到11点间中的枪
8:00 and 11:00 p.m. last night.
那么晚教堂还对外开放吗
Kind of late for a church to be open to the public, isn't it?
没开放  教区人说
It wasn't... the sisters of the Parish said
教堂6点就已锁门了
the place was locked at 6:00,
但今早发现
but discovered this morning
前门被人撬开了
that the front door had been jimmied.
怎么  大卫是和凶手一起闯进来的吗
So, what... Dave and the killer broke in together?
不太像  证据显示
Doubt it... evidence shows
凶手是偷偷溜进来  躲在一扇祈祷用的
that the killer snuck in and shot Dave from behind
装饰性彩窗后面  枪击了大卫  击碎了玻璃
what was a decorative stained-glass window for prayer.
不是吧
Really?!
怎么回事
What is going on here?
神父  你认识大卫·约翰逊
Father, did you know Dave Johnson?
是啊  他是个忠诚的教区居民
Oh, yes. He was a faithful Parishioner.
您是否知道
Do you have any idea
大卫昨晚为什么会来教堂
what Dave was doing at the church last night?
不知道
Not a clue.
或许他妻子知道
Perhaps his wife knows.
你们跟温迪谈过了吗
Have you spoken to Wendy?
不  我们还没通知家属呢
No. We haven't notified her yet.
你能跟我们说说大卫吗
But what can you tell us about Dave?
他有什么仇人吗
Did... did he have any enemies?
没有
Oh, no.
他是个好人  忠诚的丈夫
He was a good man, a loving husband,
可以说是最伟大的
and arguably one of the greatest...
什么
Greatest what?
这反正也要曝出来
Well, it's going to come out sooner or later.
大卫是近50年来
Dave was one of the greatest novelists
最伟大的小说家
of the last 50 years.
大卫·约翰逊
Dave Johnson?
没听过啊  神父
Uh, I've never heard of him, father.
那是因为他用了假名
That's because he wrote under a pseudonym.
爸爸  你听说了吗
Dad? Did you hear?
爸爸
Dad?
那是我的小马  你别摸
It's my pony! You can't pet it!
你的小马
Your pony?
什么
What?
怎么了
What's up?
P·J·莫菲特死了
P.J. Moffet's dead.
P·J·莫菲特是我的文学英雄之一啊
P.J. Moffet was one of my literary heroes.
也是我的
Mine too.
我八年级还写过关于他的论文  记得吗
Remember, I wrote that paper about him in eighth grade.
每位作家都梦想写下伟大的美国小说
Every author dreams of writing the great American novel,
但P·J·莫菲特真做到了
but P.J. Moffet actually did it.
而且是一举成名  《伯劳鸟之歌》
On his first try, too... "The butcherbird's song."
25年来  他再未写过东西
And in 25 years, he never wrote another word.
一本书  就从公众视野中消失了
Just one book, then he disappeared from public life.
据推特上的消息
According to twitter,
他在3大街的圣马克教堂被杀
he was murdered at St. Mark's on 3rd.
太好了
That's wonderful.
爸爸  对死者尊敬一点啊
Dad, a little respect for the dead.
不是他被杀好
Not wonderful that he was murdered...
是他被杀地点太好了
Wonderful where he was murdered.
圣马克教堂
St. Mark's...
那是12分局的辖区
That's in the jurisdiction of the 12th precinct,
而我可是个P·J·莫菲特的专家
and I am an expert on all things P.J. Moffet.
看来你还是要继续这个"跟贝克特一起破案
So you're still going with the "Win Beckett back
进而赢回她"的计划
by working homicides with her" Plan?
她一开始就是这么爱上我的
That's how I got her to fall for me the first time --
一起办案  还有...我吻她的时候  我用...
That and...when I kiss her, I use the bottom --
爸  你提到性生活的时候
Dad, when it comes to your sex life, how about
咱们能不能还是走剪辑版的路线
we stick with the "Afterschool special" version?
可以接受
That's fair.
很好  那你这次打算怎么介入这案子
Okay, so, what's going to be your way into the case this time?
我只需要...
Well, all I need is, uh...
一个客户
A client.
喂  蕾妮打电话来了
You guys, Lanie called.
现场没发现有用的指纹
No usable prints from the crime scene,
也没留下弹道痕迹
And no hits off ballistics.
《伯劳鸟之歌》还是算很火的小说吧
"The butcherbird song" Is still a popular novel, right?
虽然已经25年了
I mean, it's 25 years old,
但被害人应该依然有大笔版税入账
but our victim should still be getting huge royalty checks.
对  大部分高中都把它列入必读书单了
Yeah. It's required reading in most high schools.
那为什么过去五年来  他会住在单身公寓里
Then why was he living in a one-bedroom apartment
还做着门卫的工作呢
and working as a janitor for the past five years?
我给出版商打电话问问  让他们确认下他的身份
I'll call the publisher, have them confirm who he is.
不用了
No need.
我们能帮忙
We can do that for you.
卡塞尔  你怎么来了
Uh...Castle, what are you doing here?
来见见我的客户
Meet my client.
这是温迪·约翰逊  大卫·约翰逊的妻子
This is Wendy Johnson, wife of Dave Johnson,
后者就是著名的小说家P·J·莫菲特
also known as famed novelist P.J. Moffet.
我们是来录口供的
We're here to make a statement.
我们带她去贝克特警监的办公室
Well, we'll...escort her to Captain Beckett's office.
你的客户  卡塞尔
Your client, Castle?
别告诉我是你去死缠烂打的
Please don't tell me you ambulance-chased this woman.
贝克特  这么说可太过分了
Beckett, that is an outrageous accusation.
我  作为作家协会的一员
I, as a member of the writing community,
只是去她家表示了一下关心
merely went by her home to offer my condolences.
我猜你还告诉她你是私家侦探了吧
And I suppose you told her that you're a P.I.
而且正好跟纽约警局还有点关系
who just happens to have connections with the NYPD.
可能不小心提到了这些
The topic may have come up.
啊对了  你真美啊
You look gorgeous, by the way.
我们该去跟你的客户谈谈了
Uh, we should go and talk to your client.
我们才刚结婚八个月
We'd only been married for eight months.
可我觉得好像认识他一辈子了
I felt like I'd known him my entire life.
也许因为那本书伴随了我的成长吧
Probably because I grew up just loving that book.
说到这个  约翰逊太太
Uh, yeah, about that, Mrs. Johnson --
您丈夫已经如此成功了
Considering your husband's success,
为什么还要去当门卫呢
why was he working as a janitor?
他是为了新书在做调查
Well, that was research for a new book.
第二本P·J·莫菲特的小说吗
A second P.J. Moffet novel?
他调查了五年
He was doing research for over five years?
莫菲特为了写书
Moffet was legendary
能投入得走火入魔  这很有名
for total immersion in his subject matter --
就像我对你一样
Much like me with you.
你知道吗  在《伯劳鸟之歌》动笔前
Uh, did you know that before writing a single word
莫菲特曾花了七年时间
of "The butcherbird song," Moffet spent seven years
过着爱斯基摩瘾君子般的生活
living as a drug-addicted eskimo?
是真的
It's true.
他对自己的作品无比专注
He was extremely dedicated to his craft.
他在怀俄明州有一大片农场
Even though he owns a ranch in Wyoming,
可他却坚持婚后要住在布鲁克林  体验真实生活
He insisted we live in Brooklyn for authenticity.
他昨晚为什么要闯入圣马克教堂
Why did he break into St. Mark's church last night?
我只能猜测他是去祈祷的
I can only guess it was to pray.
他最近非常困扰
He had been extremely troubled recently.
你知道是为什么吗
Do you know about what?
我觉得是跟他的调查有关
I think it had to be his research.
大卫离开的时候
When Dave left,
跟我说他那天早上见了个人
he told me he met with someone that morning,
局面有点失控
and things got heated.
他见了谁
And who did he meet with?
他没说  只说那人很危险
He didn't say -- just that the man was dangerous.
他的新书要写什么题材
Well, what was his new book about?
黑手党
Um, the mafia.
卡塞尔呢
Where's Castle?
送他的客户回家了
He took his client home.
记住  他不再是跟我们一起办案了
Remember, he doesn't work cases with us anymore.
我查到被害人昨天上午在哪里了
So, I found out where our vic was yesterday morning.
根据他的开支记录来看
According to his financials,
他打了辆车去布鲁克林
he took a cab ride to Brooklyn.
他在哪下的车
Where was he dropped off?
这人家  米尔顿·西塞罗
This guy's house -- Milton Cicero.
做公共卫生的
Works in sanitation.
据说他是个彻底的黑手党
Word is he's totally mobbed up.
要是被害人在为他的新书做调查
If our vic was doing research for his book
并且问了太多问题
And he asked too many questions,
米尔顿也许起了疑心
Milton here might have gotten suspicious
并除掉了他
and taken Dave out.
好吧
Okay.
他确实来过我这儿
He did come to my house,
可我没杀他  我发誓
but I didn't kill him -- I swear.
-那你怎么认识他的  -我不认识
- So, how do you know him? - I don't.
他突然就跑来了  开始问我各种问题
He just came over, started asking me all these questions.
什么问题
About what?
关于工会回扣
Union kickbacks.
他想知道钱是哪来的
He wanted to know where all the money comes from.
我说
Say...
你俩知道他的真实身份吗
You two have any idea who he really is?
知道  他是P·J·莫菲特  小说家
Yeah. He's P.J. Moffet, the novelist.
P.J.啥  什么家
P.J. What? The what?
才不是
No.
他是"双枪"吉米·奥麦利
That is Jimmy "Two guns" O'malley.
啥  等等...
Wait. Wha-- uh...
那个爱尔兰黑帮分子
The irish mobster
80年代出卖了全部同伙的那个
who ratted out his whole crew back in the '80s?
就是他
Bingo.
他开始跟我说起证人保护的事
He starts telling me all about witness protection
还说局里给了他新名字  大卫·约翰逊
and how the feds gave him a new name -- Dave Johnson.
等等  黑帮不是发了悬赏
Hold up -- doesn't the mob have a contract out
要"双枪"吉米的命吗
on Jimmy "Two Gun's" life?
有吗
Do they?
我完全不知道啊
I wouldn't know anything about that.
米尔顿
Milton?
你是不是想要得到那份悬赏
Did you try to collect on that reward?
别跟我说
Don't tell me that
你给波士顿的黑帮打了电话
you made a call up to the mob in Boston.
我没有  没给他们打电话
I didn't... not call them.
好的  再见
Okay, bye-bye.
我刚跟P·J·莫菲特的出版商通过电话
So, I just got off the phone with P.J. Moffet's publisher.
那位作家活得好好的
Our author is still very much alive.
大卫·约翰逊对身份撒了谎
Dave Johnson was lying about who he was.
是的  我们也知道了
Yeah, we figured.
大卫跟米尔顿说
So, Dave tells Milton that
他就是"双枪"吉米·奥麦利
he's Jimmy "Two Guns" O'malley,
然后米尔顿就向爱尔兰黑帮揭发了他
and then Milton rats him out to the Irish mob.
可能死者是个骗子
Maybe our vic was a con man.
骗了不该骗的人结果害死了自己
And conning the wrong guy got him killed.
贝克特警监
Captain Beckett?
联调局给你回复了
You heard back from the FBI?
是的  很有可能是爱尔兰黑帮
Yeah, it's looking more and more like the Irish mob
杀死了大卫
are responsible for Dave's murder.
比利·欧洛克  南波士顿疑似杀手
Meet Billy O'Rourke, a suspected hit man from Southie.
据说他昨天下午到了肯尼迪机场
Word on the street is he landed at JFK yesterday afternoon.
他还在城里吗
Is he still in town?
两分钟前
Well, as of two minutes ago,
他还没有从比尔莫酒店退房
he hadn't checked out of the Biltmore Hotel.
好的
Okay.
跟埃斯波一起把他带回来
Go find Espo and pick him up.
好的
Yeah.
莱恩
Ryan?
注意安全
Be careful.
知道了
You got it.
他在里面吗
Is he in there?
好的  谢了  赶紧离开这儿
All right, thanks. Get out of here, kid.
她跟我说她需要空间
So, she's telling me she needs space.
我觉得她是急需帮助
I'm saying that's a cry for help.
是的  里克  我完全同意
Yeah, Ricky. I completely agree.
谢谢
Thank you.
纽约警局
NYPD!
伙计们  你们  你们饿不饿
Hey, guys! How are -- are you hungry?
抱歉  我们没有点穿防弹衣的笨猪这道菜
Sorry. Neither of us ordered pigs wrapped in Kevlar.
出去
Get out.
赶紧站起来  欧洛克
On your feet right now, O'Rourke.
卡塞尔  你怎么在这
Castle, how'd you get here?
我送大卫妻子回家的时候
When I gave Dave's wife a ride home,
我看到了一张昨天的收据
I saw a receipt from yesterday --
大卫夹克快速干洗的收据
A rush dry-cleaning job on Dave's jacket.
账单邮寄地址写的这里
The bill was charged to this room.
你们怎么来了
How did you get here?
联调局
The FBI.
卡塞尔  这个人
Castle, this guy --
他是爱尔兰黑帮的杀手
he's a hit man for the Irish mob.
不  是的  是的
No! Well, yes, yes.
不过等你了解他后
But w-when you get to know him,
就会知道他是个好人
he's actually really a l-lovely person.
他是个很好的倾听者
You know, he's a -- he's a good listener.
-是的  -谢谢你听我说
- Yeah. - Thank you for that.
-非常热情  -没错
- Very hospitable. - There you go.
而且他还告诉我大卫...
And he actually told me that Dave...
里克  他们是警察  别说了
Ricky, they're cops. Shut up.
不  他们是我认识的警察  没事的
No, they're my cops, though. These guys are okay.
只是
Just --
伙计们  比利不是你们要找的凶手
guys, Billy's not your killer.
你怎么知道的
Oh, you know this how?
比利告诉我的
Billy told me.
是啊
Yeah.
那他有没有在胸前画个十字祈祷赶紧死去呢
Oh, and did he also cross his heart and hope to die?
比利  把你跟我说的告诉他们
Billy, tell them what you told me.
好吧
Okay.
假设性地说
Let's say, hypothetically...
假设
Hypothetically.
我来这里杀"双枪"吉米
I came to town to whack Jimmy "Two Guns"
假设
and, hypothetically...
我把他丢进我租来的车的后备箱里
I threw him in the trunk of my rental
然后带他去了梅多兰泽的沼泽地里
and drove him out to the marsh by the Meadowlands.
你们知道那个地方
You know where that is.
只是
Only, just before --
当然还是假设
hypothetically... of course.
在我冲他开枪之前  我意识到
I could put a bullet through his brain, I realized
这人一点也不像"双枪"吉米
the guy doesn't look anything like Jimmy "Two guns."
好吧  大卫解释了这都是误会
Right? So Dave explains it's all just a misunderstanding,
-他其实是P·J·莫菲特...  -是的
- that he's actually P.J. Moffet... - Yeah.
他跟别人说他是"双枪"吉米
and he's telling everybody he's Jimmy "Two Guns"
是为了能为自己的小说做调查
so he can do research for his new novel.
是的  我非常喜欢他的小说
Yeah, and I'm a huge fan.
《伯劳鸟之歌》  我太喜欢了
"The Butcherbird Song" -- it's my everything.
简直太...我自己也有一本
Oh, please. That's -- I have a copy myself.
别开枪
No, no!
比利把大卫带回这里
So Billy brings Dave back here,
然后他付钱帮他洗了夹克
and he pays to have his jacket cleaned.
是的  他还在书上给我签了名
Yeah. He even autographed the book for me.
太好了  不是吗
Oh, isn't that lovely?
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
我也不想戳破你们的幻想
Oh, hate to burst your bubble, though.
可他根本不是P·J·莫菲特
He ended up not being P.J. Moffet after all.
他是个骗子
Guy was a con man.
-不是吧  -真的吗  不要啊
- Come on! - Really?! No!
还有  卡塞尔  无论你怎么说
And, by the way, Castle, no matter what you say here,
这都无法证明
it doesn't prove
你的新死党比利  没有杀大卫
that your new BFF, Billy, didn't off Dave.
是的  可是他有不在场证据
No, it doesn't, but his alibi does.
-是的  -在案发时
- Yeah. - At the time of the murder,
他正坐在第一排看《狮子王》
he was front row at "The Lion King."
或许可以说是城里最棒的音乐剧
Arguably the best musical in town.
是啊  你说的没错
Yeah, well, you're not wrong.
但是  告诉他们
But tell them what you saw
你把大卫塞车里前看见什么了
before you put Dave in the trunk.
-假设的说  -假设的说
- Hypothetically. - Hypothetically.
我绑架大卫前  我看见他
Yeah, before I snatched up Dave, I saw him
在公寓外面和一个高个子的人
having this knockdown, drag-out argument
激烈的争论
with some tall guy outside his apartment house.
这个人对大卫说
So the guy says to Dave,
你最好遵守你的承诺
"Hey, you better come through, like you promised,
否则会有严重的后果
or there's gonna be serious consequences."
承认吧  他是个挺好的人
Admit it -- he's not so bad of a guy.
卡塞尔  就算他的不在场证明成立
Castle, just because his alibi held
另外他还付了午饭钱
and he paid for lunch
也不意味着他是好人
doesn't make him a great humanitarian.
他以杀人谋生
He kills people for a living.
对  但是如果没有他这样的人
Yes, but without people like him,
我们这样的人就要失业了
people like us would be out of a job.
我们接下来去干什么
Now, what's our next move?
找到这个神秘人  核实他的身份
Locate and identify this mystery man?
不  那是我们要去干的事
No. That's our next move.
你下一步要回家
Your next move is to go home.
贝克特不想让你来调查这案子  抱歉
Beckett doesn't want you working the case. I'm sorry.
不  我明白  完全理解
No. Uh, I get it. Totally understand.
我回去  给我的客户汇报情况
I'll circle back 'round and, uh, update my client.
卡塞尔
Castle.
这  这有点过了
That's -- yeah. That's too much.
噢  警监  我的警监
O captain, my captain.
卡尔
Carl.
谢谢你从鉴证科过来
Thank you for coming up from CSU.
我需要你帮我介绍一下毒品的特性
I need you to give me a rundown of narcotic signatures --
明确说是海洛因
Specifically heroin.
基本上  每一批海洛因都像雪花一样
Basically, every batch of heroin is like a snowflake.
每一批都不一样
No two are alike.
要决定样本是否来源于同一批货
To determine if samples are from the same batch, we run
我们用色析法分析杂质特征
a chromatographic impurity signature profile analysis.
明白
Okay.
如果说我有一份海洛因样本
Um, let's say I have a sample of heroin
然后我把它与另一份样本对比
and I compare it to another sample,
这就可以帮我确定
and that'll help me determine
他们是否来自于同一来源
whether they originated from the same source?
正是
Exactamundo.
谢谢  这正是我所需要的
Thank you. That's all I needed.
你好吗  卡尔
What's up, carl?
你为什么找鉴证组负责毒品的人过来
Hey, what are you meeting with CUS's narcotics guy for?
你知道  埃斯波  我还有其他
You know, Espo, I do have other cases
需要监管的案子
that I have to supervise.
抱歉  警监
My apologies, captain.
寻找那个神秘人有什么进展吗
So, any luck on finding that mystery man?
莱恩正在看大卫家附近的街道监控录像
Ryan's scrubbing street-cam footage near Dave's apartment.
但我觉得我们遗漏了一些细节
But, yo, I think we're missing something here.
什么意思
What do you mean?
如果大卫是一个诈骗大师
Well, if Dave was a scam artist,
他就是我所知道最奇怪的一个
he is the oddest one I ever heard of.
他确实表现出了骗子的行为
I mean, yes, he was exhibiting con-man behavior,
但为了什么
but to what end?
为了骗人
Uh, to rip people off.
骗谁  他妻子
Who? His wife?
她并非来自有钱家庭
She didn't come from money.
那个神父宣誓恪守清贫
The priest took a vow of poverty.
至于那个工会的家伙  大卫没跟他要过钱
And the union guy -- Dave never asked him for a payoff.
对  有道理
Okay, that's a good point.
那么大卫的骗局有什么利可图呢
So what's the upside to Dave's cons?
我确定威胁大卫的神秘人的身份了
So, I I.D.'d our mystery man who threatened Dave.
他叫埃里克·洛根  他是个被定罪的诈骗大师
Guy's name is Eric Logan. He's a convicted scam artist.
两次袭人
Two collars for assault,
其中一次还是用了致命武器
including one with a deadly weapon.
也许埃里克和大卫在一起设下骗局
You know, maybe Eric and Dave were working a con together
但出了些问题
and something went wrong.
你知道埃里克现在在哪吗
Any idea where Eric is now?
知道  我追踪了他的手机  我们有他的定位
Yeah. I pinged his cell. We got a location.
我们去接他吧
Let's go pick him up.
证据室
Evidence Room.
我是贝克特警监
Yeah, this is captain Beckett.
我们还有瓦肯·西蒙斯案件中
Do we still have the seized heroin
缴获的海洛因吗
from the Vulcan Simmons case?
等一下  让我核对一下
Hang on. Let me check.
我等
Yeah, I'll hold.
是的  还有
Yes, we do.
很好
Good.
就这样吧
That's all I needed.
好吧  无论如何谢谢你
All right. Well, thanks anyway for trying.
坏消息
Hey, bad news.
警长考试已经没有空位了
There's no more slots open for the sergeant's exam.
该死
Damn!
我猜我们只能等着
Well, I guess we're gonna have to wait
下次有机会了
till the next slot opens up.
三点钟方向有情况
Boogie three o clock.
纽约警局
NYPD!
天啊
Geez!
卡塞尔
Castle.
我正要去
I was just going to that, uh...
我正要去那边的便利店
Just going to the bodega there.
买东西  牛肉干什么的  你们呢
Pick you something up -- little slim jim, yoo-hoo?
卡塞尔  你怎么知道我们在这
Castle, how did you know that we were here?
你是不是趁那个尴尬拥抱时
Did you put this tracker on me
往我身上放了这个追踪器
when you gave me that awkward hug?
我完全不知道那是什么
I have no idea what that is.
但我愿意从你手上拿过来
But I'll take it off your hands.
当然  给你
Yeah, sure. Here you go.
你知道我还能找到它  对吧
You know I can find that, right?
伙计们  那是埃里克
Hey, guys. It's Eric.
但我这辈子从来没有过好机会  你明白吗
But I never really had a fair shot in life, you know?
我的父母
Uh, my parents --
他们在我小的时候死于空难
They died in a plane crash when I was a kid.
那是骗你们的
That's a lie.
事实上  我父母现在住在丹佛
Actually, my parents live in Denver.
克利夫兰
Cleveland.
不管怎样  我叫史蒂夫
Anyway, uh, my name's Steve.
谢谢大家
Thanks for listening.
谢谢  鲍勃
Thanks, Bob.
结束之前  朋友们今天是个悲痛的日子
Before we close, friends, today is a sad day,
因为我们失去了我们的一员
because we just lost one of our own --
大卫·约翰逊
Dave Johnson.
他的经历也是个警示  因为昨晚
His is a cautionary tale, because last night...
大卫的谎言最终让他得到了惩罚
Dave's lies finally caught up with him.
让我们为大卫默哀
Let's take a moment for Dave.
这是什么  戒酒匿名会吗
What is this, an A.A. Meeting?
PLA
P.L.A.
那是什么玩意
What the hell is P.L.A.?
病态撒谎者匿名会
Pathological liars anonymous.
完全说得通了
Makes perfect sense.
大卫不是骗子  他是病态撒谎者
Dave wasn't a con man. He was a pathological liar.
太可笑了
This is rediculous.
我没有杀害大卫
I didn't kill Dave.
-他是我朋友  -你确定吗
- He was my friend. - You sure about that?
因为他被害当天
Because the day he was killed,
有人看到你威胁他
a witness saw you threatening him.
我是他的担保人  他遇到了麻烦
I was his sponsor. He was in trouble.
我逼他来参加
I was pushing him to attend
病态撒谎者匿名会集会
the Pathological Liars Anonymous Meeting.
这就对了  就是这样
Yeah! That's the ticket. That's it.
-记得吗  -对
- Remember? - Oh, yeah.
你怎么敢  先生
How dare you, sir.
强迫性病态说谎
Compulsive and pathological lying
是一种由心理创伤引起的精神疾病
is a mental disorder caused by psychological trauma.
不是什么能拿来说笑的事情
This is not something to joke around about.
好吧
Okay. Fine.
但我们怎么能相信你说的事情
But, then, how can we believe anything you say about Dave?
你都承认自己是个撒谎者了
You're a self-confessed liar.
我已经洗心革面了
I'm reformed.
我立誓要诚实  保证不再撒谎
I took a vow of honesty, a pledge to refrain from lying.
算了吧
Come on.
每个人都会说谎
Everybody lies.
我不会  再也不会了
Not me -- not anymore.
-说点小谎都不会了吗  -不会
- Not even a little fib? - No.
-善意的谎言呢  -不会
- A white lie? - No.
我可以向你证明
I can prove it to you.
你可以问问我对你写作的看法
Ask me what I think about your writing.
你觉得我写的怎么样
What do you think of my writing?
我觉得你妄想成为帕特森
I think you're a Patterson wannabe,
我觉得你最新一本就是无聊的改写而已
And I think your last book was a boring retread.
看到了吗  无情的真相
You see? Brutal truth.
不是  那只是刻薄
Uh, no. That's just being mean.
不  这是诚实  不像你
No, honest -- unlike you,
一个明显穿着内增高的人
A man who obviously wears lifts
这样就可以谎报身高了
so he can lie about his height.
才不是  这不是内增高
No, no. T-these aren't lifts.
只是定制的鞋垫而已
These are custom, prescription insoles.
你有什么好笑的
What are you laughing about?
你明显是染了头发  好隐瞒年龄
You clearly dye your hair so you can lie about your age.
只是鬓角稍微有一点
Just -- just a little bit in -- in the temples.
好吧  就假定你说的
Okay, l-l-let's assume what you're saying...
是
Is...
是真的
Is true.
你说大卫有麻烦
You said Dave was in trouble.
是什么样的麻烦
What kind of trouble?
是几周前开始的
It started a couple weeks ago.
他又犯病了
He fell off the wagon.
开始无法控制地撒谎  他很害怕
He started lying out of control, and he was scared.
害怕什么
Scared of what?
他发现了一些事情
And he had uncovered something --
一些危险非法的事情
Something dangerous, illegal.
为什么他不报警呢
Why didn't he come to the cops?
他对太多人说过太多谎
Oh, he'd lied so many times to so many people --
甚至他的妻子
Even his own wife --
他知道没有人会相信他
He knew nobody would believe him.
他就是狼来了故事里面的男孩
He was the boy that cried wolf.
不管是什么
But whatever it was,
他说他需要找到证据才能把这事公开
he said he needed proof before he could go public.
把什么事公开
Go public with what?
他不知道
He didn't know.
你觉得这个担保人说的是真的吗
And you think that this sponsor's telling the truth?
就目前来看是的
Well, as far as we could tell.
此外他的不在场证据很可靠
Plus, his alibi is rock-solid for the murder.
我们得查明大卫两周前
We got to figure out what Dave was onto
到底发现了什么  让他丧了命
two weeks ago that got him killed.
已经在查了
Already on it.
干得好伙计们  明天早上见
Great job, guys. I'll see you in the morning?
-好的  -辛苦了
- All right. - Thanks.
卡塞尔的短信
Text from Castle.
我也收到了
Yeah, me too.
来我这  很重要
"My place. Important."
也许他有什么发现
Maybe he found something.
我们怎么办
What do we do?
我们去他那  看看到底是什么
We go over to his place. We find out what's what.
不管我们做什么  我们不...
Whatever we do, we don't...
当然不
Oh, hell no.
但是万一她发现了怎么办
But what if she finds out?
我们撒个谎就没事了
We lie our asses off.
对
Yeah.
等等  你听到什么了
Wait -- do you hear something?
没有
No. Don't think so.
你好  朋友们
Hola, amigos!
欢迎光临卡塞尔之家
Bienvenidos a casa Castle, huh?
很好  非常好
Nice! Very nice!
先生们  非常棒
Gentlemen, very nice.
喝点什么吧
Grab a drink.
这是什么情况
Uh, what is this?
这只是我向我在12分局的家人
This is just me saying thank you
表达我的谢意
to my family at the 12th precinct.
你想收买我们
You're trying to buy our love.
-什么  -好让我们帮你赢回贝克特
- What?! - So we'll help you win Beckett back.
才不是  兄弟们
No! Come on, guys.
这是给你们的
These are for you.
你让我们很难办
Well, you're putting us in a really tough spot here.
你知道我们也是贝克特的朋友
You know we're friends with Beckett, too.
更何况贝克特现在是我们上司
Plus, Beckett's our boss now.
她不想让你插手案子
She doesn't want you working cases.
伙计们  我爱她  记得吗  我要赢回她
Guys, I love her, okay? And I'm gonna get her back.
而我唯一能想到的方法
The only way I know how to do that
就是和她一起解决谋杀案  所以我不会放弃
is solving murders together, so I'm not going anywhere.
所以别管那些  放松享受一番吧
So sit back, relax, and enjoy the ride.
试试玉米脆饼  那上面可是神户牛肉
And try the tostadas. They're wagyu beef.
我倒是想尝尝神户牛肉
Ah. I do love me some wagyu.
谢谢
Thank you.
怎么啦
What's up?
噢  没事
Oh, nothing.
珍妮她  她想让我
Uh, jenny just -- you know, she wants me
回家路上顺便带点东西
To pick up some stuff on the way home.
是吗
Really?
不过那个短信怎么写着"警长考试"呢
'cause that text message said "Sergeant's exam."
好吧  我之前或许说了点小谎
Okay. Uh, I may have lied...earlier.
之前确实有职位开放报考  但是只有一个
There was an exam slot open, but only one.
你就报名了  却根本就没跟我说
So you took it -- without even talking to me?
-哥们  那可是我的主意  -很抱歉
- Bro, that was my idea. - I'm sorry.
你知道我最近有多缺钱
You know how stressed out about money I've been lately.
加薪对我相当有帮助
A bump in pay would really help.
哈维  别走啊
Javi -- hey!
得了  别说了
No. Save it.
莱恩  我刚不小心听到你说
Hey, Ryan, I couldn't help but overhear
你有些经济困难
about your financial concerns.
也许我们可以合作
Maybe you and I could work together.
怎么合作
How?
就当是替我搞点小副业
Do a little, uh, moonlighting for me.
只要把12分局的动静都告诉我一声
Just keep me in the loop as to what's going on at the 12th.
你想让我给你当内奸  才不要呢
You want me to be a rat for you? Hell no.
我一周付你500美元
I would pay you $500 a week.
我干
I'll do it.
嘿  好搭档
Hey, partner.
餐车在附近  我就给你买了早餐
Food truck is here, so I got you some breakfast --
双份辣酱  就是你喜欢的那种
double salsa, just the way you like it.
谢谢了
Oh. Hey. Thanks.
你做什么
What the hell?
我只是像你对待我一样处理了那个玉米煎饼
Uh, I was just treating that burrito like you treated me.
是的我向你撒了谎  对不起
Okay, I lied to you. I'm -- I'm sorry.
我有需要承担的责任
I have responsibilities.
我猜你的责任不包括
I guess looking out for your partner's back
关照你的搭档
Isn't one of them.
你们没事吧
You guys okay?
好着呢  怎么啦
Fine. What's up?
我需要你们去一趟市政厅
I need you to go down to city hall.
大卫的老板说他两周前在那边
Dave's boss said that Dave had an incident there
出了点纠纷  所以他所属的门卫公司
two weeks ago, and his janitorial company
不得不把他调去别的部门看门
Was forced to reassign him to another facility.
什么纠纷
What kind of incident?
我想她就是要让我们去那里
I think that's what she's sending us down there
查清楚是什么纠纷
to find out.
好的  我们这就去
Yeah, we're on it.
好
Okay.
你有什么消息告诉我
What have you got for me?
看来
Yeah, apparently,
受害者在市政厅跟人发生过冲突
our vic had some sort of confrontation down at city hall,
我们正要去跟他们的办公室副主任谈谈
so we're running down there to talk to the deputy chief of staff.
我也爱你  亲爱的  再见
I love you, too, sweetie. Bye-bye.
怪怪的
That was weird.
什么
What?
莱恩跟我说他爱我
Ryan just told me he loved me.
我确定他只是在打掩护
I'm sure he was just covering.
难道你把他变成你的内鬼
Don't you feel the least bit conflicted
就一点都没有过意不去吗
about turning him into a mole?
他又不是在盗窃国家机密
He's not stealing state secrets.
我只是雇他帮我跟进他们的案情
I'm just paying him to keep me in the loop on their cases.
然后你就能在该案件中拼命炫技
So you can ingratiate yourself in said cases
找到新的方法和贝克特套近乎
and find new ways to interact with Beckett.
如果你说的"拼命炫技"
Well, if by "Ingratiate myself,"
意思是说"用我福尔摩斯般的睿智打动她"
You mean "Dazzle her with my Sherlockian genius,"
那么  没错  我就是要这么做
Then, yes, that's exactly what I mean.
那么  莱恩说了什么
So, what did Ryan say?
受害人在市政厅惹过一些麻烦
That our victim got himself into some trouble at city hall
也许他就是因为这个被杀的
that might have got him killed.
所以你看我给我的市长好哥们打个电话怎么样
So what do you say we call my good buddy the mayor?
大卫就是个门卫  老爸
Dave was a janitor, dad.
我强烈怀疑市长会注意到他
I sincerely doubt he was on the mayor's radar.
我们解雇了大卫·约翰逊
We fired Dave Johnson
因为他闯进了会计办公室
after he broke into the accounting office.
而且保安抓住他的时候他还试图逃跑
And he tried to run when security caught him.
那么  被抓住的时候他说什么了吗
Well, what did he say when they caught him?
一些胡言乱语
Oh, some nonsense
上帝派给他的任务什么什么的
about being on a mission from god or something --
考虑到他得到这份工作的原因
which was incredibly disrespectful,
那些话实在是非常无礼
Given how he got the job in the first place.
他怎么得到的
And how's that?
他是圣马克教堂的阿圭罗神父推荐来的
Oh, he was recommended by father Arguello at st. Mark's.
那个盲人神父
The blind priest?
是的  怎么
Yeah. So?
大卫在阿圭罗的教堂被杀了
Dave was killed in arguello's church.
我不是警探  不过这听起来像个线索
Well, look, I-I'm no detective, but that sounds like a clue.
抱歉我失陪一下
Uh, if you'll excuse me...
看来我们得跟神父谈谈了  走吧
Looks like we need to talk to the good father. Let's go.
等等  稍等一下
Oh, wait. Just a second.
我先跟珍妮说句话
Um, make a quick phone call to Jenny.
马上过去
Be right there.
上帝的任务
A mission from god?
莱恩是这么说的
Well, that's what Ryan said.
但是  大卫是个说谎强迫症
On the other hand, Dave was a compulsive liar.
但大多数谎言还是包含一点真相的
Still, most lies have a kernel of truth in them.
就像你去时装周的时候
Like when you went to fashion week,
故意没有提到
but you neglected to mention
你是拿着我的白金卡去的
That you were taking my platinum credit card?
我把更多的心思放在被害人身上
I was more thinking about our victim
他谎称自己是逃亡的暴徒
and how he lied about being a fugitive mobster
怎么会跟调查工会回扣扯上关系呢
in order to investigate union kickbacks.
回扣可能会跟市政厅有关联
Kickbacks that could be connected to City Hall --
所以  大卫就闯进了会计室
Hence, Dave breaking into the accounting office.
但这些事跟盲人神父有什么联系呢
But what does any of this have to do with a blind priest?
问[求]  就必得着[约翰福音16:24]
Ask, and ye shall receive.
打扰了  神父
Uh, excuse me, father.
我们在调查大卫·约翰逊的谋杀案
We are investigating Dave Johnson's murder.
鉴于您跟他的关系
We'd like to ask you a few questions
我们想问您几个问题
regarding your relationship with him.
我是他的神父  孩子
I was his priest, my son.
我给他精神上的指引
I gave him spiritual guidance.
究竟哪部分指引
And which part of that guidance
会让他非法闯入市政厅呢
included breaking and entering at City Hall?
盲人神父居然跑起来了
The blind priest just ran away.
完了要撞上了
This cannot end well.
-看着点  -小心
- Hey! - Hey, watch it!
我们是不是该...
Should we...
该死  追
Damn it. Yes.
什么
What?!
让我概括一下
So, let me get this straight --
你被一个盲人神父甩了
You got parkoured by a blind priest?
我要说  他是否失明值得商榷
I'd say the blindness is under dispute.
那他已经60高龄了  你又该怎么说呢
And what about the fact that he's 60?
他的年龄也是假的吗
Was he faking his age, too?
60岁老当益壮赛20
60 is the new 20.
你打电话就是为了取笑我的吗
Did you call just to bust my chops?
是啊  差不多吧
Yeah. Pretty much.
好了  飞毛腿  我要挂了
Um, all right, speedy, I got to go.
睡前一定要做拉伸运动啊
Make sure you stretch before bed.
他们抓住那个神父了
They got the priest.
你怎么知道的
How do you know?
贝克特有点太开心了
Beckett was having too much fun.
等等
Wait.
贝克特在跟我开玩笑
Beckett was having fun -- with me.
得分
Score.
设想一下她审问那个落跑神父会有多开心吧
Imagine how much fun she's gonna have with the runaway priest.
我能跟你说实话吗
Can I be honest with you?
我装瞎是为了逃离坦帕市
I went blind to get out of Tampa.
那里的日子简直不是人过的
It was miserable down there.
潮湿的天气让人难以忍受
The humidity was just oppressive.
当我得知如果神父有某些残疾
When I learned that priests with certain disabilities
就可以选择分配的地方  我丝毫没犹豫
have their pick of assignments, I-I didn't even hesitate.
我不明白这些跟
I don't understand what any of this
大卫·约翰逊的谋杀案有什么关系
has to do with Dave Johnson's murder.
大卫爱撒谎的毛病是他沉重的负担
Dave's lying was a terrible burden --
他从童年时就开始背负这个负担
One that he'd been carrying since childhood.
我给他指了一条赎罪的路
I offered him a way to make amends.
你现在还在说实话是吗
And this is you still being honest?
是的
Yes.
大卫说谎的毛病毁了他的会计生涯
Dave's lying torpedoed his accounting career.
所以他才在市政厅做门卫
That's why he was working as a janitor at City Hall,
假装自己是隐居的作家
pretending to be a reclusive author.
我的教区有笔给市里的税款马上就要欠缴了
My parish was about to miss a payment to the city,
因为我...  资金管理不善什么的
due to my... mismanagement of funds.
我就要求大卫偷偷潜入会计部
I simply asked Dave to sneak into the accounting office
在电脑上把这笔税款登记为已缴纳
and log the payment into the computer as received.
所以你才不在乎赎罪啊
So this wasn't about making amends.
你是想帮自己的忙
This was about helping you.
当大卫侵入市政预算系统时
When Dave was hacked into the city budget,
他发现了一笔秘密贿赂资金的证据
he found evidence of a secret slush fund --
从社保项目中抽取了一千万
$10 million siphoned from social programs
放进了某人的腰包
to line someone's pocket.
这个谎言大卫无法忍受
It was a lie Dave couldn't stomach,
所以他发誓要揭露此事
so he vowed to expose it.
而你认为控制那笔
And you believe that whoever controlled
所谓贿赂资金的人
this alleged slush fund
发现了大卫闯入一事
discovered Dave's intrusion?
他们因此杀了他
And they killed him for it.
你认为呢
Do you think?
这跟受害者对其担保人说的话相吻合
It tracks with what our victim told his sponsor.
跟大卫对工会回扣的质疑也吻合
And with Dave's questions about union kickbacks.
这不重要  这根本没什么用
It doesn't matter. It's non-actionable.
我们不可能仅凭一个装瞎神父
There's no way we're gonna get a subpoena for City Hall
从一位病态撒谎者那听来的话
based on hearsay told to a not-blind priest
就传唤市政厅
from a pathological liar.
我想大卫是对的
I guess Dave was right --
没有人会相信爱说谎的人说的话
No one believes the boy who cries wolf.
那你说该怎么办  放弃吗
So what are you saying -- we give up?
那可不是我认识的贝克特会做的事
Because that's not the Beckett that I know.
不  我没说要放弃
No, I'm not saying that we should give up.
我要说的是  我才刚就任警监
What I am saying is, I've been a captain for about five minutes.
如果我们就这么上报地检
If we take this to the D.A.,
以后就没人会把我当回事了
nobody's gonna take me seriously ever.
好吧  我们会找到证据的
Okay. We'll get proof.
钱肯定找不到了
Money's gone.
就算的确有一笔贿赂资金
Even if there is a secret slush fund,
控制它的人杀了大卫灭口后
the person controlling it killed Dave to cover it up,
肯定把钱藏了起来  抹去所有痕迹了
buried the money deep, covered his tracks.
那我们又该怎么找呢
So what are we supposed to do?
我们仔细查
We do our homework.
我们去查谁可以从市政预算中调出贿赂资金
We find out who could pull off a slush fund in the city budget,
也就是说我们必须去找
which means we have to talk to someone
在市政厅有关系的人
with contacts and resources in City Hall.
某位和市长是好哥们的人
Someone who's best friends with the mayor?
比如...  卡塞尔
Someone like... Castle?
这样会让他洋洋得意的
He's gonna be so smug about this.
抱歉  你刚才说什么  需要我帮忙吗
I'm sorry. Did you say you... needed my help?
卡塞尔
Castle.
你听见她的话了  是吗
You heard her say it, right?
-爸爸  别闹了  -多谢
- Dad, let it go. - Thank you.
卡塞尔  你到底有没有我们需要的情报
Castle, do you have the intel we need or not?
你跟她说
Tell her.
我上中学的时候
When I was in middle school,
爸爸对市政资金的内部运作
dad did four months of extensive research
进行了为期四个月的深入调查
into the inner workings of city finance
为他正在写的小说搜集素材
for a novel he was writing.
是的  可然后我意识到那本小说
Yes, but then I realized that that novel would be
会成为小说史上最无聊的一本
the most boring novel in the history of novels,
所以我就改写德里克·斯道姆系列丛书了
so I wrote a Derek Storm book instead.
好吧  那么你很清楚
Okay, so, then, you have a pretty good idea
哪些市公务员
of which city officials
有能力藏匿一千万美金的贿赂资金
would be able to hide a $10 million slush fund.
是的  符合条件的人不多
Yes, and it's a pretty small list.
可以接触到全部预算的人只有
The only people with access to the entire budget
审计主任  市长的办公室主任
are the comptroller, the mayor's chief of staff,
和副主任
and the deputy chief.
史蒂芬·里德  我们见过那个人
Stephen Reed -- the guy we met with.
我确定办公室主任
I know for a fact that the chief of staff
现在正陪同市长在伦敦出访
is in London with the mayor.
我也打了几个电话偷偷地问了一下
And I made a few discreet calls.
大卫被杀时  市审计主任正在
The city comptroller was at a fundraiser
出席筹款活动
when Dave was shot.
也就是说里德是我们的头号嫌疑犯
Which means Reed is our main suspect.
好吧  那我们怎么抓这家伙呢
Okay, so, how do we get this guy?
我提议用《午夜狂奔》中的策略
May I suggest the "Midnight Run" stratagem?
-什么策略  -《午夜狂奔》
- The what? - "Midnight Run."
这可是影史排名前五的拍档电影
It's one of the top five buddy movies of all time.
而你建议我们遵照这个警察搭档电影
And you're suggesting we base our legal strategy
来制定我们的执法策略
upon this buddy-cop movie?
不  他说得对  或许行得通
No, he's right. It could work.
在电影的最后
At the end of the movie,
罗伯特·德尼罗设计让匪徒去取一张
Robert de Niro tricks a mobster into taking computer discs
他以为含有他犯罪证据的数据盘
he thinks contain evidence against him,
匪徒只要去取这些数据盘
and just by showing up to take them,
就会因妨碍司法公正被抓现行
the mobster is committing conspiracy to obstruct justice.
如果我们也同样设计里德
If we can trick Reed the same way,
那我们就有了足够的把柄
then we've got all the leverage we need
来揭露贿赂资金
to expose the slush fund
并且追查他跟大卫谋杀案的关系
and go after him for Dave's murder.
但是凯特  你不能参与
But, Kate, you can't be involved.
为什么
Why not?
因为万一里德与此事无关
Because if Reed isn't involved,
那整个行动就会对我们不利
then all this blows up in our face,
而你将会背上责任
and you take the hit.
你不能背这锅
And you don't need that.
让我们挡在你前面吧  警监
Let us shield you, Captain.
好吧
Okay.
我不参与  暂时而已
I'm out -- for now.
谢谢
Thanks.
好吧  咱们怎么做
Okay, how do we do this?
首先我要借用一下你们的盲人神父
First, I'm gonna need to borrow your blind priest.
里德先生
Mr. Reed?
Mr. Reed!
神父
Father.
你怎么在这
What are you doing here?
你办公室的人说我可以在这找到你
Uh, your office told me where to find you.
抱歉神父
Ah. Well, sorry, Father.
见我必须先预约  神职人员也是一样
I'm appointment-only, even for the clergy.
我认为你不会希望办公室的人听到
I don't think you want your office to hear
我要跟你谈的事的
what we're about to discuss.
大卫·约翰逊是我教会里的信徒
Dave Johnson was one of my flock.
他被炒是因为他闯入了自己不该去的地方
Who got fired for being where he didn't belong.
是的  但大卫告诉我  他闯入后
Yes, but while he was there, Dave told me
不小心发现了你的秘密小账户
he stumbled across your little secret account.
我不知道你在说什么
Uh, I have no idea what you're talking about.
我的热狗已经做好了  我
And, uh, my hot dog's waiting, so --
大卫是个谨慎的人  里德先生
Dave was a cautious man, Mr. Reed.
他拿到了关于那个账户的证据
He took proof of the account --
他把证据存在了一个闪存盘中
proof that he left on a thumb drive
并在被害之前将其放在我教堂祭坛的
on the altar of my church behind the chalice
圣餐杯后面
before he was killed.
我把这个消息当作礼物送给你
I give you this information as a gift.
而作为答谢  如果你能把教堂的欠款
If you were to make the church's debt disappear,
一笔勾销的话
as a token of appreciation,
主会感激你的
well, the lord would be grateful.
这个嘛
Well...
正如我所说的  神父
Like I said... Father...
我完全不知道你在说什么
I got no clue what you're talking about.
再也别来找我了
Don't ever come see me again.
愿上帝保佑你  我的孩子
Bless you, my child.
成功了吗
Think it worked?
当然
Of course it worked.
今晚就知道成不成功了
We'll know tonight.
肯定会成功
That it worked.
好吧
All right.
你知道该怎么做
You know what to do.
你确定吗
Are you sure about this?
玩大点要不就干脆回家待着
Go big or go home,
只不过这一次  监狱就是家了
except...in this case, home might be jail.
是他吗
Is that him?
不知道
I don't know.
肯定是他
It's got to be him.
不许动  纽约警局  站住  里德
Don't move! NYPD! Stop! Reed!
闪存盘没了
It's gone.
该死的
Damn it!
-他跑哪去了  -我们搞砸了
- Where'd he go? - We're screwed.
整个妨碍执法指控都建立在
Catching him with that empty thumb drive
抓到他拿着那个空白的闪存盘上
was our whole conspiracy charge.
成功了吗
Did it work?
什么成功了吗
Did what work?
是你把灯给关了吗
Are you the one that turned the lights out?
是我  我让她去关的
I-I told her to do that.
你为什么要干这种事
Why in the hell would you do that?
我认为我们的《午夜狂奔》策略
Well, I thought our "Midnight Run" stratagem
需要一点小转折
needed a little twist.
相信我  伙计们  这次成功的话
Trust me, guys -- if this works,
我们控告他的就不只是妨碍司法公正了
we're gonna have him on a whole lot more than just obstruction.
要是不成功呢
What if it doesn't?
我是理查德·卡塞尔  私家侦探
Hi. I'm Richard Castle, private investigator.
你把这个闪存盘
The moment you plugged this thumb drive
插入电脑的一瞬间
into your computer,
它就在你的系统上植入了病毒
it injected a virus into your system.
现在那个病毒已经搜索了你的按键历史
By now, that virus has searched your keystroke history
并且查出你把贿赂资金藏到了哪里
and found where you've moved your hidden slush fund.
这就是电脑版的爆炸染料包
It's the computer equivalent of an exploding dye pack.
看来我们还可以再给你加一条
So, I guess we can add destruction of city property
破坏公共财产的罪名
to those charges.
我没杀他
I didn't kill him.
我图什么呢  他是个骗子
Why would I? He was a liar.
再说  我有不在场证明
Plus, I have an alibi.
哦  让我猜猜  你一个人在家睡觉吗
Oh, let me guess -- you were home, alone, asleep?
不  我在和你们的上司  警察局长玩扑克
No, I was out playing poker with your boss, the police commissioner.
这说明你们的凶手还逍遥法外
Which means your killer's still out there.
所以  我们现在都知道什么
So, what do we know?
大卫·约翰逊  病态撒谎者
Dave Johnson -- he was a pathological liar
偶然发现一笔秘密的贿赂基金
who stumbled upon a secret slush fund
然后决定揭发这件事
and then decided to expose it.
而所有与此相关的人都有不在场证明
And everyone connected to that alibi'd out.
所以我们毫无进展
So we've got nothing?
不  我们可以肯定大卫是因为说谎被杀的
No. We can safely assume that Dave was killed over a lie.
那么是哪个谎
Which lie, then?
如果是我来写  我会始终围绕一个主题
Well, if I was writing this, I would fall back on a theme.
谎言是对信任的背叛
A lie is a betrayal of trust.
而最严重的背叛  莫过于婚姻中的谎言了
And there is no greater betrayal... than a lie in a marriage.
好吧  也许是这样
Yeah, well, that might be,
但温迪以为大卫是P·J·莫菲特
but Wendy thought that Dave was P.J. Moffet.
如果她发现他不是呢
What if she found out he wasn't?
你们完全搞错了  我没杀大卫
You have this all wrong. I didn't kill Dave.
我们在你的车上找到了彩色玻璃的碎片
We found fragments of stained glass in your car.
与教堂碎掉的玻璃窗相匹配
It matches the broken glass found in the church.
我只是因为大卫说他是个名作家才嫁给他的
I only married Dave because he told me he was a famous author.
我  我只是觉得这样我就能过上奢侈的生活
I-I just -- I thought I was gonna be living in luxury.
但是他坚持过穷日子
And -- and he insisted that we live in poverty,
即使他身家巨万
even though he had millions.
可惜  他在说谎
Only, he was lying.
而你发现了这点
And you found out.
我不明白的是  你为什么要杀了他
You know, what I don't understand is, why would you kill him?
你为什么不离婚算了
Why didn't you just divorce the guy?
因为他要为我的损失  付出代价
Because he had to pay. For what he cost me.
我本来能嫁给拿骚县的地毯大亨本·沙皮罗
I could have married Ben Shapiro, the carpet king of Nassau county.
然而谁成想  我嫁给一个毁了我生活的骗子
But instead, I married a liar who ruined my life.
温迪·约翰逊  你因谋杀
Wendy Johnson, you are under arrest
你丈夫而被捕
for the murder of your husband.
等等  等一下
Wait. Wait!
这几天  你就会收到发票
In a few days, you're gonna receive an invoice.
如能立即付款我不胜感激
I'd appreciate prompt payment.
嗨  停  停一下
Hey, hey! Stop! Stop, stop, stop!
听着
Listen.
我会给总局打电话
I'm gonna call 1PP,
我会让他们把我那个
and I'm gonna ask them to give you
仅剩的警长考试考位给你
that last sergeant's exam slot instead of me.
我不需要你的施舍
I don't need your charity.
这不是施舍
It's not charity.
我不该那么对你
Hey! Hey, I did wrong by you.
我在试图改正
I'm trying to make amends here.
傻哥俩
Hey, bozos.
你们就从没有想过你们的警监
Did it ever occur to you that your captain
可以动用点关系给你们每人一个考位吗
could pull some strings and get you both a slot?
你可以吗
Did you?
没错
Yeah.
而且我希望你们能通过
And I expect you to pass.
今天干得漂亮
Good job today.
-多谢警监  -谢了警监
- Thanks, captain. - Thanks, captain.
好了
All right.
好运  哥们儿
Good luck, man.
卡塞尔
Castle?
别紧张  没什么别的意思
Relax. Doesn't mean anything.
这不过是一杯庆祝
It's just a little congratulatory coffee
解决棘手案子的咖啡
after solving a tough case.
我总是没办法泡的像你一样好喝
I can never make it like you.
虽然你教过我怎么做
Even though you taught me how.
那是因为我撒谎了
That's 'cause I lied.
有一味很特殊的原料  我隐瞒了
There's a, uh... special ingredient. I kept it a secret.
真的
Really?
是什么
What is it?
好吧  如果我现在告诉你
Well, now, if I told you that,
你也许就不再需要我了
you might not need me anymore.
那就不要告诉我
Then don't tell me.
既然我们彼此坦诚
And since we're being honest,
有些事我得告诉你
there's something that I have to tell you.
我讨厌莫菲特的书
I hated Moffet's book.
什么  什
What?! Wha--
你以前为什么不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
因为那是你在刚开始和我约会的时候送给我的
Because you gave it to me when we first started dating,
我知道那对你来说很重要
and I knew it was important to you,
所以  我撒谎了
So...I lied.
我很抱歉  我得接这个电话
I'm sorry. I have to get this.
晚安
Have a good night.
你也是
You too.
维克拉姆
Vikram. Hey.
你拿到瓦肯·西蒙斯案子里
Did you get the test results on the heroin
海洛因的化验结果了吗
from the Vulcan Simmons case?
很好
Good.
现在我们可以动手了
Now we can get to work.